# Xiaole Zhao

Southwest Jiaotong University

Western zone of chengdu high-tech zone, China Phone:  $+86-15881624882 \mid QQ: 1023270208$   $\bowtie$  zxlation@foxmail.com/zxlation@swjtu.edu.cn  $\stackrel{\frown}{=}$  https://zxlation.github.io/xiaole.github.com  $\stackrel{\frown}{=}$  https://github.com/zxlation/xiaole.github.com



I am an assistant professor in the School of Computing and Artificial Intelligence, Southwest Jiaotong University (SWJTU), Chengdu, China. My research interests mainly include image restoration/generation, machine/deep learning and pattern recognition etc. Recently, I have been working on low-level computer vision tasks of medical images with deep learning techniques.

	EDUCATION
Sep. 2016 – Jun. 2020	Biomedical Engineering, The School of Life Science and Technology, — Ph.D. University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (UESTC), Chengdu, China Advisor: Prof. Mark Zou (Founder of Alltech Medical System Co., LTD) and Tao Zhang Overall GPA: 3.56/4.0, Major GPA: 3.62/4.0
Sep. 2013 – Jun. 2016	Software Engineering, The School of Computer Science and Technology,  Southwest University of Science and Technology (SWUST), Mianyang, China Advisor: Prof. Yadong Wu  Overall GPA: 3.72/4.0, Major GPA: 3.70/4.0
Sep. 2009 – Jun. 2013	Software Engineering, The School of Computer Science and Technology,  Southwest University of Science and Technology (SWUST), Mianyang, China Overall GPA: 3.64/4.0, Major GPA: 3.66/4.0
	RESEARCH EXPERIENCE
Oct. 2021	Assistant Professor, Southwest Jiaotong University, Chengdu, China.  Research: Computer Vision, Image Processing, Deep Learning, Artificial Intelligence.
Jul. 2020 – Jan. 2021	Research Assistant, Southwest University of Science and Technology, Mianyang, China. Research: Computer Vision, Image Processing, Deep Learning, Artificial Intelligence.
Sep. 2016 – Jun. 2020	Ph.D Candidate, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, China.
	Research: Medical Image Analysis, Magnetic Resonance Imaging, Deep Learning  Project Officer, Alltech Medical System Co., LTD, Chengdu, China.
Jun. 2020	Research: Medical Image Analysis, Magnetic Resonance Imaging, Pattern Recognition, Deep Learning
	PROJECT PARTICIPATION
Jan. 2019 – Dec. 2020	Key Laboratory for NeuroInformation of Ministry of Education, Chengdu, China.  Supervisor: Prof. Tao Zhang  Project: Research of multimodal magnetic resonance neuroimaging on the efficacy of antidepressants and the outcome mechanism of cognitive function in elderly depression  Source: Key Projects of Application Foundation in Sichuan Province
	Key Laboratory for NeuroInformation of Ministry of Education, Chengdu, China.
Jun. 2020	Supervisor: Prof. Tao Zhang Project: A new imaging mechanism of high field magnetic resonance – tissue dielectric tomography and its application in clinical diagnosis of breast and brain tumors Source: National Key R&D Projects
_	Laboratory of Virtual Reality and Visualization, Mianyang, China.
Oct. 2015	Supervisor: Prof. Yadong Wu Project: Research on models and algorithms for image super-resolution reconstruction Source: Key Projects of Application Foundation in Sichuan Province
_	Laboratory of Virtual Reality and Visualization, Mianyang, China.
Oct. 2015	Supervisor: Prof. Yadong Wu Project: Single image super-resolution based on blind blur estimation and anchor space mapping Source: Key Projects of Innovation Fund of SWUST

# HONORS AND AWARDS

Jan. 2009	Merit Student of Mianyang City	Top $1\%$
Jun. 2010	First Prize of Annual Advanced Mathematics Competition of SWUST	Top $1\%$
Nov. 2010	National Scholarship (B.S.)	Top $1\%$
Mar. 2011	Merit Student of Mianyang City	Top $3\%$
Jan. 2013	Outstanding Graduate of Sichuan Province	Top $1\%$
Apr. 2014	First Prize of Graduate Scholarship	Top $1\%$
Nov. 2015	National Scholarship (M.S.)	Top $1\%$
Dec. 2015	Outstanding Master Graduates of Sichuan Province	Top $1\%$
Oct. 2018	Second Prize of Postgraduate Scholarship	Top $5\%$

# — PROGRAMMING SKILLS

# ★ Programming Languages

Matlab, C/C++, Python, LATEX, OpenCV

## ★ Deep Learning Tools

TensorFlow, Keras, MatConvNet

# — ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

### ★ Journal Reviewer

 $\star$ 

⋆

	• IEEE Computational Intelligence Magazine (CIM)	2021		
	• IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging (TMI)	2020		
	• The Visual Computer (TVCJ)	2017		
t	Conference Attendance			
	o International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, Sydney, Australia.	2020		
	o International Conference on Intelligence Science and Big Data Engineering, Nanjing, China.	2019		
	• Chinese Conference on Pattern Recognition and Computer Vision, Guangzhou, China.	2018		
	o International Conference on Computational Visual Media, Cardiff University, UK.	2016		
	o Chinese Conference on Computer Vision, Xi'an, China.	2015		
Membership				
	• China Computer Federation ( <b>CCF</b> )	2021		
	• Sichuan Informatics Association of Traditional Chinese Medicine	2021		

### PUBLICATIONS

• Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)

Overview I have published more than 10 papers on reputable journals and conferences like TIP, TCSVT, CVPR, ICME, CVIU and Neurocomputing etc. Most of these papers focus on a low-level computer vision task, i.e., image super-resolution, but also involve deep learning, dictionary learning, pattern recognition and other related fields. My academic homepage is located at https://zxlation.github.io/xiaole.github.com.

2019

### Journal

Haoqian Wang, Xiaowan Hu, Xiaole Zhao and Yulun Zhang. "Wide weighted attention multi-scale network for accurate MR image super-resolution." IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology, Accepted, 2021.

- [J2] Xiaole Zhao, Yulun Zhang, Tao Zhang, Xueming Zou, "Channel splitting network for single MR image super-resolution." IEEE Transactions on Image Processing, vol. 28, no. 11, pp. 5649–5662, 2019.
- [J3] Xiaole Zhao, Yadong Wu, Jinsha Tian, Hongying Zhang, "Single image super-resolution via blind blurring estimation and dictionary learning." Neurocomputing, vol. 212, pp. 3–11, 2016.
- [J4] Xiaole Zhao, Xiafei Hu, Ying Liao, Tian He, Tao Zhang, Xueming Zou, Jinsha Tian. "Accurate MR image super-resolution via lightweight lateral inhibition network." Computer Vision and Image Understanding, 2020, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cviu.2020.103075.

- [J5] Xiaole Zhao, Huali Zhang, Yuliang Zhou, Wei Bian, Tao Zhang, Xueming Zou, "Gibbs-ringing artifact suppression with knowledge transfer from natural images to MR images." Multimedia Tools and Applications, pp. 1–23, 2019.
- [J6] Xiaole Zhao, Yadong Wu, Jinsha Tian, Hongying Zhang, "Single image super-resolution via blind blurring estimation and anchored space mapping." Computational Visual Media, vol. 21, no. 1, pp. 71–85, 2016.

### Conference

- [C1] Xiaowan Hu, Zhihong Liu, Ruijun Ma, Yuanhao Cai, Haoqian Wang, **Xiaole Zhao**, and Yulun Zhang. "Pseudo 3D auto-correlation network for real Image denoising." In: **CVPR**, Virtual Event, 2021:
  - 16175-16184.
- [C2] Xiaowan Hu, Haoqian Wang, Yuanhao Cai, Xiaole Zhao, Yulun Zhang. "Pyramid orthogonal attention network based on dual self-similarity for accurate MR image super-resolution." In: ICME, Shenzhen, China, 2021: 1-6.
- [C3] Xiaole Zhao, Xiafei Hu, Tao Zhang, Xueming Zou. "Isotropic MRI reconstruction with 3D convolutional neural network." In: ISMRM, Sydney, Australia, 2020.
- [C4] **Xiaole Zhao**, Tao Zhang, Xueming Zou, "A lightweight lateral inhibition network for single MR image super-resolution." In: **IScIDE**, Nanjing, China, 2019.
- [C5] Xiaole Zhao, Hangfei Liu, Tao Zhang, Wei Bian, and Xueming Zou, "Multilevel residual learning for single image super resolution." In: PRCV, Guangzhou, China, pp. 537–549, 2018.
- [C6] Xiaole Zhao, Yadong Wu, Jinsha Tian, and Hongying Zhang, "Single image super-resolution via blind blurring estimation and anchored space mapping." In: CVM, Cardiff University, UK, 2016.
- [C7] Xiaole Zhao, Yadong Wu, Jinsha Tian, Hongying Zhang, "Single image super-resolution via blind blurring estimation and dictionary learning." In: CCCV, Xi'an, China, pp. 22–33, 2015.

## CONTACTS

### Mark Zou University of Electroic Science and Technology of China

Ph.D Supervisor.

USA Instruments (Current GE Coils Department), President & CEO

GE Medical Group, Vice President of Medical Department

Picker (Now Philips Medical Department), Senior Scientist

Alltech Medical System Co., LTD, Founder & CEO

 $\textbf{Email:} \ \, \text{mark.zou@alltechmed.com}$ 

### Tao Zhang University of Electroic Science and Technology of China

Ph.D Supervisor.

Laboratory of National High Magnetic Field (USA), Research Assistant

GE Global R & D Center, Senior Engineer

Alltech Medical System Co., LTD, Vice President of R & D, CTO

Email: taozhangjin@gmail.com

# Yadong Wu Southwest University of Science and Technology

M. S. Supervisor.

China Computer Federation, Senior Member

CCF YOCSEF, Vice Chairman

Sichaun University of Science and Engineering, Dean

**Email**: wyd028@163.com